Guide to the Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences Records SC1055
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences records
1952-2010
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Tyler, Ralph Winfred
Wilson, O. Meredith
Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences at Stanford University
SC1055
100 Linear Feet (80 boxes)
Administrative records of the Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences include executive director's correspondence, Board of Directors meeting minutes and agendas, financial records, reports, grant files, statistical information on Center fellows, and other records.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The records were transferred to the Stanford University Archives by the Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences in August 2011; August 2012; and May 2015.
Information about Access
The collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 48 hours in advance of intended use.
Biographical/Historical note
The Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences at Stanford University (CASBS) is a national and international resource that exists to extend knowledge of the principles governing human behavior to help solve the critical problems of contemporary society. CASBS offers a residential postdoctoral fellowship program for scientists and scholars from this country and abroad. Since 1954, CASBS fellowships have been awarded to scholars working in a diverse range of disciplines. These include the five core social and behavioral disciplines of anthropology, economics, political science, psychology and sociology as well as scholars from a wide range of humanistic disciplines, education, linguistics and the biological sciences.
Scope and Contents
Administrative records of the Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences include correspondence of the executive director, Board of Directors meeting minutes and agendas, financial records, reports, grant files, statistical information on Center fellows, and other records.
Social sciences -- Research.; Social sciences -- Study and teaching.; Tyler, Ralph Winfred; Wilson, O. Meredith; Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences at Stanford University; Wilson, O. Meredith; Tyler, Ralph Winfred; Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences at Stanford University
- Administration, 1952-1989; Series 1
  - Frank Stanton Papers, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Frank Stanton Correspondence, 1953-55 (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
  - Frank Stanton, Early Records, 1953-61 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Ralph Tyler, Misc. Correspondence, 1954 Sept 17 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - CASBS Opening Press Releases, 1953 June (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - The Ford Foundation Behavioral Sciences Division Report, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - CASBS Sites-California, 1971-76 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Program on Science, Technology and Society (POSTS), General Reports, 1968, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - CASBS Publicity Booklets, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Program on Science, Technology and Society (POSTS) Information, 1954-55 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Fellows Mobility Notes, 1959-60, 1963-64 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Fellows Academic Interests, 1959-60 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Administrative Documents and Form Letters, 1954-63 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Fellows' Rosters, 1947-58 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Statistics on Fellows, 1952 June (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Planning Group Report, 1956-57 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Fellows' Activities, 1955-56 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Fellows' Evaluations, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Fellows' Program, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Evaluations, Ford Foundation, 1955 April 22-1956 July 27 (Box 1, Folder 21-22)
  - Notices to Fellows, 1954 Feb 13 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Articles of Incorporation, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, Seminar on Sociology of Knowledge, 1959-67 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - "Cutting Edge" Proposals and Projects, 1954-55 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Notices to Fellows (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Notices to Fellows and Staff, 1956-1958 July (Box 1, Folder 28-29)
  - Notices to Fellows and Staff, 1958 Oct-1960 Dec (Box 1, Folder 30-31)
  - Notices to Fellows and Staff, 1961 Jan-1965 June (Box 1, Folder 32-33)
  - Notices to Fellows and Staff, 1965 June-1969 June (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Notices to Fellows and Staff, June 1965-June 1969 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Notices to Fellows and Staff, 1969 July-1973 Aug (Box 2, Folder 3-5)
  - Tyler, Ralph, Outgoing Correspondence, 1961-1967
    - Ralph Tyler, Outgoing Correspondence, 1961 Oct 24-1961 Dec 29 (Box 2, Folder 6-7)
    - Ralph Tyler, Outgoing Correspondence, 1962 Jan 1-1962 Mar 30 (Box 2, Folder 8-10)
    - Ralph Tyler, Outgoing Correspondence, 1962 Apr 2-1962 Jun 29 (Box 2, Folder 11-12)
    - Ralph Tyler, Outgoing Correspondence, 1962 Jul 6-1962 Sep 28 (Box 2, Folder 13-14)
    - Ralph Tyler, Outgoing Correspondence, 1962 Oct 1-1962 Dec 31 (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
    - Ralph Tyler, Outgoing Correspondence, 1963 Jan 1-1963 Apr 1 (Box 3, Folder 3-4)
    - Ralph Tyler, Outgoing Correspondence, 1963 Apr 1-1963 July 1 (Box 3, Folder 5-6)
    - Ralph Tyler, Outgoing Correspondence, 1963 Jul-1963 Sep (Box 3, Folder 7-8)
    - Ralph Tyler, Outgoing Correspondence, 1963 Oct-1964 Jan (Box 3, Folder 9-10)
    - Ralph Tyler, Outgoing Correspondence, 1964 Jan-1964 Mar (Box 3, Folder 11-12)
    - Ralph Tyler, Outgoing Correspondence, 1964 April-1964 June (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
    - Ralph Tyler, Outgoing Correspondence, 1964 July-1964 Sep (Box 4, Folder 3-4)
    - Ralph Tyler, Outgoing Correspondence, 1964 Oct-1964 Dec (Box 4, Folder 5-6)
    - Ralph Tyler, Outgoing Correspondence, 1965 Jan-1965 Mar (Box 4, Folder 7-8)
    - Ralph Tyler, Outgoing Correspondence, 1965 Apr-1965 June (Box 4, Folder 9-10)
    - Ralph Tyler, Outgoing Correspondence, 1965 July-1965 Sep (Box 4, Folder 11-12)
    - Ralph Tyler, Outgoing Correspondence, 1965 Oct-1965 Dec (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Ralph Tyler, Outgoing Correspondence, 1965 Oct-1965 Dec (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Ralph Tyler, Outgoing Correspondence, 1966 Jan-1966 Mar (Box 5, Folder 2-3)
    - Ralph Tyler, Outgoing Correspondence, 1966 Apr-1966 June (Box 5, Folder 4-5)
    - Ralph Tyler, Outgoing Correspondence, 1966 July-1966 Sep (Box 5, Folder 6-7)
    - Ralph Tyler, Outgoing Correspondence, 1966 Oct-1966 Dec (Box 5, Folder 8-9)
    - Ralph Tyler, Outgoing Correspondence, 1967 Jan-1967 Mar (Box 5, Folder 10-11)
    - Ralph Tyler, Outgoing Correspondence, 1967 Apr-1967 June (Box 5, Folder 12-13)
    - Ralph Tyler, O. Meredith Wilson, Outgoing Correspondence, 1967 July-1967 Sep (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
  - Wilson, O. Meredith, Outgoing Correspondence, 1967-1975
    - O. Meredith Wilson, Outgoing Correspondence, 1967 Oct-1967 Dec (Box 6, Folder 3-4)
    - O. Meredith Wilson, Outgoing Correspondence, 1968 Jan-1968 Mar (Box 6, Folder 5-7)
    - O. Meredith Wilson, Outgoing Correspondence, 1968 Apr-1968 June (Box 6, Folder 8-9)
    - O. Meredith Wilson, Outgoing Correspondence, 1968 July-1968 Sep (Box 6, Folder 10-11)
    - O. Meredith Wilson, Outgoing Correspondence, 1968 Oct-1968 Dec (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - O. Meredith Wilson, Outgoing Correspondence, 1969 Jan-1969 Mar (Box 6, Folder 13-14)
    - O. Meredith Wilson, Outgoing Correspondence, 1969 Apr-1969 June (Box 6, Folder 15-16)
    - O. Meredith Wilson, Outgoing Correspondence, 1969 July-1969 Sep (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
    - O. Meredith Wilson, Outgoing Correspondence, 1969 Oct-1969 Dec (Box 7, Folder 3-4)
    - O. Meredith Wilson, Outgoing Correspondence, 1970 Jan-1970 Mar (Box 7, Folder 5-6)
    - O. Meredith Wilson, Outgoing Correspondence, 1970 Apr-1970 June (Box 7, Folder 7-8)
    - O. Meredith Wilson, Outgoing Correspondence, 1970 July-1970 Sep (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - O. Meredith Wilson, Outgoing Correspondence, 1970 Oct-1970 Dec (Box 7, Folder 10-11)
    - O. Meredith Wilson, Outgoing Correspondence, 1971 Jan-1971 Mar (Box 7, Folder 12-13)
    - O. Meredith Wilson, Outgoing Correspondence, 1971 Apr-1971 June (Box 7, Folder 14-15)
    - O. Meredith Wilson, Outgoing Correspondence, 1971 July-1971 Sep (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - O. Meredith Wilson, Outgoing Correspondence, 1971 Oct-1971 Dec (Box 7, Folder 17-18)
    - O. Meredith Wilson, Outgoing Correspondence, 1972 Jan-1972 Mar (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
    - O. Meredith Wilson, Outgoing Correspondence, 1972 Apr-1972 June (Box 8, Folder 3-4)
    - O. Meredith Wilson, Outgoing Correspondence, 1972 July-1972 Sep (Box 8, Folder 5-6)
    - O. Meredith Wilson, Outgoing Correspondence, 1972 Oct-1972 Dec (Box 8, Folder 7-8)
    - O. Meredith Wilson, Outgoing Correspondence, 1973 Jan-1973 Mar (Box 8, Folder 9-10)
    - O. Meredith Wilson, Outgoing Correspondence, 1973 Apr-1973 June (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - O. Meredith Wilson, Outgoing Correspondence, 1973 July-1973 Sep (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - O. Meredith Wilson, Outgoing Correspondence, 1974 Jan-1974 Mar (Box 8, Folder 13-14)
    - O. Meredith Wilson, Outgoing Correspondence, 1974 Apr-1974 June (Box 8, Folder 15-16)
    - O. Meredith Wilson, Outgoing Correspondence, 1974 July-1974 Sep (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - O. Meredith Wilson, Outgoing Correspondence, 1974 Oct-1974 Dec (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - O. Meredith Wilson, Outgoing Correspondence, 1975 Jan-1975 Mar (Box 8, Folder 19-20)
    - O. Meredith Wilson, Outgoing Correspondence, 1975 Apr-1975 June (Box 9, Folder 1-2)
    - O. Meredith Wilson, Outgoing Correspondence, 1975 July-1975 Sep (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - O. Meredith Wilson, Outgoing Correspondence, 1975 Oct-1975 Dec (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - M.H.L. Sanders Report on Potential Sites for CASBS, 1952, Sep 12 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - M.H.L. Sanders Supplementary Report on Sites for CASBS, 1953 Aug (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - M.H.L. Sanders Site Selection Correspondence, 1953 Apr-1954 Aug (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Ralph Tyler Site Committee Correspondence, 1953 Apr-1954 May (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Site Committee, Misc. Sites, 1953-1954 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Site Committee, Mary Lyons Tract, Swarthmore, PA, 1953 Oct (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Site Selection, Misc. Correspondence, 1954 Feb-1954 May (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Ralph Tyler Site Selection Correspondence, 1954 April-1954 June (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Potential Sites-San Francisco Bay Area, 1954 Jan-1954 Apr (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Potential Sites-Hillsborough, 1953-1954 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Potential Sites-Stanford Hills, Lathrop Residence Plans, 1954 Mar (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Wurster, Bernardi Emmons, Architects: Correspondence and Plans, 1955-1962 (Box 9, Folder 16-17)
  - George Morley, Clerk of the Public Works, Construction Progress Reports, 1954 May-1954 Sep (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Huddleson, Contracts and Legal Correspondence, 1954 Dec – 1955 Mar (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - EEH-Tyler CASBS Building-General Correspondence B376.1, 1954 Mar- 1954 Nov (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - CASBS Construction Contracts Wurster, Benardi Emmons B376.1(c), 1954 Mar- 1954 Nov (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - CASBS Miscellaneous Contracts Re. Building B376.1(d), 1954 Mar- 1954 Nov (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - CASBS Building-Progress Reports, Budget, Etc. B376.1(f), 1954 Mar – 1954 Sep (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - CASBS Building-Press Clippings B376.1 (g), 1954 Mar- 1954 Apr (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - CASBS Addidtional Buildings-1955, 1955-1957 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - CASBS Furniture Layout and Receipts 1954, 1954-1957 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Paul Lazersfeld, Proposal for Social Research Training Institute, 1950 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Ford Foundation, Memos to Participants in New York Conference, 1952 Mar 29-30 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Columbia Group, Quotations Relevant for Planning of Center, 1952, Nov 19 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Ralph Tyler, Early CASBS Class Documents, 1952-1953 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Ralph Tyler, Planning Group, Notes, 1953 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Ralph Tyler, Planning Group, Reports and Minutes, 1952-1953 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Ralph Tyler, Planning Group Notes and Reports, 1952 April-1953 July (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Ralph Tyler, Planning Group Meeting Notes, 1952 May 3-4 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Ralph Tyler, Planning Group, Report, 1952 May-June (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Ralph Tyler, Planning Group Meeting Notes, 1952 Nov-Dec (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Ralph Tyler, Planning Group Correspondence, 1952-1953 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Ralph Tyler, Planning Group Minutes, 1952 April 12 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Statements on Center Purposes/Activities, 1953 (Box 11, Folder 5 -7)
  - Statements on Center Purposes/Activities, Chicago Group, 1953 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Advisory Committee, Program Statement Draft and Discussion, 1954 Jan 28 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Advisory Committee, Meeting, 1953 Oct (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Advisory Committee, Program Discussion, 1954 Feb (Box 11, Folder 11-12)
  - Pre-opening Planning and Correspondence, 1953-1954 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Advisory Committee, Meeting Minutes and Notes, 1953-1954 (Box 11, Folder 14-15)
  - Advisory Committee, Meeting, 1954 Jan 16 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Advisory Committee, Meeting, 1954 Apr 3 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Advisory Committee, Meeting, 1954 May 16 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Berelson to Merton Telegram, 1951 Nov 8 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Ford Foundation, Report of Study on Policy and Program, 1949 Nov (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Ford Foundation, Annual Reports, 1953-54, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Ford Foundation, Behavioral Sciences Div., Planning Committee, 1952 Mar 25 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Ford Foundation, Behavioral Sciences Div., Report, 1953 June (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Ford Foundation, Correspondence, 1955-1967 (Box 11, Folder 24-25)
  - Ford Foundation, Behavioral Sciences Program History (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Ralph Tyler Memo to Board, 1954 Apr 21 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - General Information on CASBS, 1957 Mar 16 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Ralph Tyler, Center Continuation Plans, 1959-1960 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Advisory Committee on Awards, Letter to Bardson, 1956 Jan 4 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Tyler to Fellows, Memo re: Biographical Data on Board of Directors, 1961 Jan (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Stanton to Heald (Ford Foundation) re: Continued Support for CASBS (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Heald Letter from Board, Second Draft re: Continuing CASBS Support, 1957 Mar 29 (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - Tyler to Board, "Policies to Guide Future Center Operations", 1959 Oct 12 (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - Tyler to Board and Board to Heald, Final Draft re: Continued Support to CASBS, 1957 Mar 16 (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - Board to Heald (Ford Foundation),Request for Materials, 1957 (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - Stanton to Gaither (Ford Foundation) Requesting More Funds, 1955 Dec 19 (Box 11, Folder 37)
  - Tyler to Board re: Ford Foundation Application, 1957 Mar 29 (Box 11, Folder 38)
  - Notes of Minutes of Board of Directors Meetings, 1953 Jan-1982 Oct (Box 11, Folder 39)
  - Board of Directors, General, 1953-1961 (Box 11, Folder 40)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Agenda and Minutes, 1953 Jan 22 (Box 11, Folder 41)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1953 April 3 (Box 11, Folder 42)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1953 June 30 (Box 11, Folder 43)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1953 Oct 9-10 (Box 11, Folder 44)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Agenda, 1954 Jan 2 (Box 11, Folder 45)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Notes, 1954 Jan 2 (Box 11, Folder 46)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Agenda Matters, 1953-1954 Jan 2 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Board of Director Meeting Agenda and Minutes, 1954 Feb 13 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Material for Board of Directors Meeting, 1954 June 28 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1954 June 28 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Agenda, 1954 Sep 18 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Agenda, 1955 Jan 6-8 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Agenda, 1955 Mar 26 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Agenda and Minutes, 1955 June 27 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Agenda, 1955 Sep 17 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Agenda, 1956 Jan 7 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Agenda, 1956 June 25 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Letter, Huddleson to Tyler, 1956 Aug 28 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Agenda and Minutes, 1957 Jan 4-5 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Agenda, 1957 Mar 23 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Agenda, 1957 Sep 14 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Agenda, 1958 Jan 10-11 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Agenda, 1958 Mar 28-29 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Agenda, 1958 Sep 6 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Agenda and Minutes, 1959 Jan 16-17 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Agenda, 1959 Feb 21 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Board of Directors, Meeting Agenda and Minutes, 1959 May 23 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Agenda, 1959 Oct 10 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Agenda, 1960 Jan 30-31 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Letter, Huddleson to Tyler re: investment of Ford Foundation Funds, 1959 Oct 29 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Agenda, 1960 Apr 9-10 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Agenda, 1960 Oct 8 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Agenda, 1961 Feb 3-4 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1961 Apr 28-29 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Agenda, 1962 Jan 19-20 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Agenda, 1962 Apr 28-29 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Agenda, 1962 Oct 26-27 (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Agenda and Minutes, 1963 Jan 25-26 (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Agenda, 1963 May 4 (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - History of the Development of the Center (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - Tentative Budget for the Center, 1952 July (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - Incorporation Draft for the Center, 1953 Jan 8 (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - Center By-Laws and new Section 12 (Box 12, Folder 37)
  - Tyler Report to the Committee on Site, 1953-1954 (Box 12, Folder 38)
  - Site Committee Report to Frank Stanton, 1953 Dec 22 (Box 12, Folder 39)
  - Subcommittee on Fellows Approval, 1953 Nov 19 (Box 12, Folder 40)
  - Articles of Incorporation, 1954 (Box 12, Folder 41)
  - Finance, 1954 (Box 12, Folder 42)
  - Program, 1954 Feb 13 (Box 12, Folder 43)
  - Tyler, Progress Report of the Center, 1954 June 23 (Box 12, Folder 44)
  - Official Opening Day of the Center, 1955 Jan 7 (Box 12, Folder 45)
  - Tyler, Meeting Notes (handwritten), 1955 Jan 7 (Box 12, Folder 46)
  - Annual Report, Draft and Notes, 1955 (Box 12, Folder 47)
  - Hill, F.F. Retirement from Center Board, 1955 (Box 12, Folder 48)
  - Program Evaluation Notes by various Fellows (Box 12, Folder 49)
  - Memo, Tyler to Fellows, 1955 Jan 26 (Box 12, Folder 50)
  - Planning Group Report, Excerpt, 1952 June (Box 12, Folder 51)
  - Center Newsletter, 1955 (Box 12, Folder 52)
  - Report of the Executive Director, 1957 Mar 23 (Box 12, Folder 53)
  - Accountants' Report, 1957 Aug 31 (Box 12, Folder 54)
  - Center "Financial Information Form" for Fellows (Box 12, Folder 55)
  - Tyler to Fellows on Board of Directors Meeting Schedule, 1956 Jan 6 (Box 12, Folder 56)
  - Selection of Fellows, 1959 Jan (Box 12, Folder 57)
  - Future of the Center, Progress Report, 1959 Mar 16 (Box 12, Folder 58)
  - Robert Merton, Summary of the Future Program of the Center, 1959 May 15 (Box 12, Folder 59)
  - Continuation of the Center, 1959 Aug 3 (Box 12, Folder 60)
  - Ralph Tyler, decription of the Center (handwritten), 1959 (Box 12, Folder 61)
  - Ralph Tyler, financing of Fellowships at the Center, 1960 July (Box 12, Folder 62)
  - Fellows Tax Status, 1960 July 1 (Box 12, Folder 63)
  - Brief Summary of Personal History Form (Box 12, Folder 64)
  - Exchange Visitor Program, correspondence, Department of State, 1954-1961 (Box 12, Folder 65)
  - Opening Up New Promising Areas for Research, 1961 Jan (Box 12, Folder 66)
  - Ralph Tyler, Letter to Former Fellows, 1961 Dec (Box 12, Folder 67)
  - Physical Plant, Service Agreements, 1953-1963 (Box 12, Folder 68)
  - Quarterly Report, 1960 Aug 26 (Box 12, Folder 69)
  - Quarterly Report, 1961 Aug 28 (Box 12, Folder 70)
  - Quarterly Report, 1963 July 31 (Box 12, Folder 71)
  - "Housing, Medical Services and Schools near the Center", 1964 Jan (Box 12, Folder 72)
  - Title IV, Civil Rights Act of 1964 and Employment, 1964-1966 (Box 12, Folder 73)
  - CASBS Tax Status, 1969 July 25 (Box 12, Folder 74)
  - Pamphlet Text (Box 12, Folder 75)
  - Preston Cutler, Retirement Letter to Margaret Amara, 1979 June (Box 12, Folder 76)
  - Staff Contact Lists (Box 12, Folder 77)
  - Quarterly Report, 1962 July 31 (Box 12, Folder 78)
  - Fellow Evaluations and Comments on Year, 1954-1955 (Box 12, Folder 79)
  - "How the Center Operates" (Box 12, Folder 80)
  - Disciplines of Fellows, 1962-1966 (Box 12, Folder 81)
  - Fellow Lists, 1954-1983 (Box 12, Folder 82-85)
  - Fellow Statistics, 1954-1959 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Alumni Lists, by field, 1954-1973 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Tyler Collection, 1954-1977 (Box 13, Folder 3-6)
  - Ten Year Report, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 7-8)
  - Bernard Berelson Correspondence, 1953-1962 (Box 13, Folder 9-10)
  - Paul H. Buck Correspondence, 1954-1962 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - D.G. Ellson Correspondence, 1953-1955 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Caryl P. Haskins Correspondence, 1960-1962 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Clark Kerr Correspondence, 1953-1960 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Mary Schmitt Correspondence, 1954-1967 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Robert R. Sears Correspondence, 1953-1962 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Frank Stanton Correspondence, 1953-1962 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Logan Wilson Correspondence, 1956-1961 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Meredith C. Wilson Correspondence, 1953-1967 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - National Science Foundation: GS-466, 1964-1968 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - National Science Foundation: renewal of GS-466, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - National Science Foundation: G 20962, 1961-1964 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Correspondence, 1959-1961 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Carnegie Corporation Correspondence, 1958-1962 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Stern Family Fund, Grants and Correspondence, 1959-1966 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Werner-Gren Foundation, support for Dr. Loren Eiseley, 1962 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Jordanian Royal Commission on Education, 1962 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Stanford Research Institute, 1962 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - NIMH Letter to B.E. Booth from Joshua A. Fishman, 1963 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Stanford University Correspondence, 1954-1963 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Fund for the Advancement of Education, 1965-1966 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Kettering Foundation Correspondence, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Stanford University Library-Acknowledgement of Gifts, 1970-1974 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Regional Selection Meeting and Correspondence, 1960-1962 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Regional Selection Meeting, Western Reserve University, 1964 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Ford Foundation Correspondence, 1953-1957 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Sidney Siegel Memorial Fund, 1962-1970 (Box 14, Folder 8-9)
  - Sidney Siegel Memorial Fund Financial Records, 1962-1975 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Center Visitors, General Correspondence, 1962-1963 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Center Visitors, General Correspondence, 1965-1970 (Box 14, Folder 12-13)
  - Center Visitors, Foreign, General Correspondence, 1963-1970 (Box 14, Folder 14-17)
  - Inquiries, General Correspondence, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 18-19)
  - Preston Cutler Correspondence, 1953-1961 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Inquiries, General Correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Inquiries, General Correspondence, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Inquiries, General Correspondence, 1966-1968 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Center, Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1954-1965 (Box 15, Folder 4)